

# CARLOS MARIO NASAYÓ VALVERDE

Phone: 3106070677

**E-Mail:** carlosnasayov@gmail.com

Website: https://carlosnasayo.github.io/curriculumvitae/

LinkedIn: Carlos Mario Nasayó Valverde

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Systems engineer with two years of experience in software development, both in frontend and backend technologies. I have solid knowledge in databases, both relational and non-relational, as well as in unit testing, integration and continuous deployment of software. I am familiar with agile methodologies for development. I have participated in several projects, both nationally and internationally, where I have developed software tools that have been widely accepted by customers. I am characterized for being results oriented and for keeping myself constantly updated in the most used technologies nowadays.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Software testing

December 2021 - February 2022

## Corporación Universitaria Comfacauca

- Implementation of integration tests for a coffee export software in the Colombia Innova (Colinova) project, improving its operation and ensuring its efficiency.
- Implementation of black box testing for a coffee export software in the Colombia Innova project (Colinova).
- Implementation of white box testing for a coffee export software in the Colombia Innova project (Colinova).

#### **Professional Practice**

April 2022 - September 2022

Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical (CIAT)

- Support in the development of forms for data capture using ODK (Open Data Kit).
- Requirements gathering and software architecture development process for a progressive web application for soil moisture data visualization.
- Development of progressive web application for visualization of soil moisture data.

# Fullstack Developer Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical (CIAT)

October 2022 - Present

- Frontend development of a gap analysis application to facilitate the collection of genetic material by alliance researchers.
- Contribution in the construction of a new module for a chatbot previously implemented in the alliance, in order to allow users to obtain estimates of coffee yields.
- Support in continuous delivery practices and continuous deployment in each project in which it is required, following these principles and also support in documentation tasks, such as the elaboration of requirements and software architecture.
- Backend development, ETL and user management for a water point monitoring platform in Ethiopia.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Systems Engineer**

February 2018 - June 2022

Corporación Universitaria Comfacauca

### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Technical Skills: React js, Flask, Javascript, Python, MongoDB, PostgresSQL, MySQL, Jenkins, Git, GitHub, Docker.
- Languages: English, Spanish.
- Certificates: Meta back-end developer professional certificate (Coursera), Full-stack web development with React specialization (Hong Kong University of Science and Technology) (Coursera).